Guide to the Jean Gonzalez Papers, 1977-2006 and undated RL.11015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jean Gonzalez papers
1977-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Paz, Juana Maria
RL.11015
0.4 Linear Feet
Collection comprises writings by Jean Gonzalez/Juana Maria Paz, 1977-2006 and undated, reflecting the breadth of her work and interests, from lesbian feminism to intential community and the lesbian land movement, with a primary focus on community building. Includes journal articles and book chapters, letters to the editor, newsletters, plays, and position statements, often in both draft and published form. Many of these works comprise her signature works in lesbian and feminist theory. Also includes architectural plans and drawings for her home in Twin Oaks.
Provenance
The Jean Gonzalez papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in April 2015.
Historical note
Jean Gonzalez, a.k.a. Juana Maria Paz, is an author, dramatist, and lesbian feminist, born in New York of Puerto Rican heritage. Since 1990, she has lived in Virginia as a resident in the intentional collective and ecofeminist community Twin Oaks.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: Writings and Plans.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises writings by Jean Gonzalez/Juana Maria Paz, 1977-2006 and undated, reflecting the breadth of her work and interests, from lesbian feminism to intential community and the lesbian land movement, with a primary focus on community building. Includes journal articles and book chapters, letters to the editor, newsletters, plays, and position statements, often in both draft and published form. Many of these works comprise her signature works in lesbian and feminist theory. Also includes architectural plans and drawings for her home in Twin Oaks.
Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Women's rights -- United States; Communal living -- United States; Lesbian feminism; Minority women; Lesbians -- United States; Gonzalez, Jean; Paz, Juana Maria
- Writings, 1977-2006; 7 folders
  - On communal living, lesbian land movement, 1990-1995 and undated (Box 1)
  - Short fiction, 1979, 1987 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    "Vision of the Enchanted Forest" and "Desire and Consequences: Sleeping with a Strange Man."
  - Plays, 1977-1990 (Box 1)
    "Dead Men-- A Woman's Fantasy," "The Ancient Matriarchy of Atlantis," "Frankly, My Dear...I'm Eating," and "Autobiographical Monologue."
  - Book, anthology chapter, 1980-1995 (Box 1)
    The LA LUZ Journal, and chapter in Heatwave, Women in Love and Lust: Lesbian Short Fiction.
  - Letters to the editor, articles, 1986-2006 (Box 1)
    Almost entirely from the print news journal "Off Our Backs."
  - Other writing, Autiobiographical works, 1984-1996 and undated (Box 1)
  - Writings by others, 1991 (Box 1)
    Somebody to Love: A Guide to Loving the Body You Have.
- Plans, undated, 1 folders
  - Twin Oaks architectural drawings, undated (Box 1)